Pease, Arthur Stanley, 1881-1964. Arthur Stanley Pease correspondence and compositions, 1870-1963 (MS Am 1804): Guide.
Arthur Stanley Pease correspondence and compositions,
- I. Letters to Arthur Stanley Pease
  - Sherrill, Henry Knox, bp., 1890- 1 letter; 1939., (780)
  - Shields, M. Lawrence. 1 letter; 1951., (781)
  - Shipley, Frederick William, 1871- 1 letter; [1940], (782)
  - Shippman, [ ] 1 letter; 1931., (783)
  - Shorey, Paul, 1857-1934. 3 letters; 1925-1931., (784)
  - Sihler, Ernest Gottlieb, 1853- 6 letters; 1923-1934., (785)
  - Silk, Edmund T. 2 letters; 1945-1946., (786)
  - Sills, Kenneth Charles Morton, 1879-1954. 6 letters; 1928-1941., (787)
  - Singer, Charles, 1876- 2 lettes; 1951., (788)
  - Sinnen, Jean. 1 letter; 1960., (789)
  - Skinner, Edward L. 1 letter; 1948., (790)
  - Slaughter, Moses Stephen, 1860-1923. 1 letter; [1908]., (791)
  - Smiley, Charles Newton. 14 letters; 1908-1941., (792)
  - Smith, George Vivian, 1876- 1 letter; 1945., (793)
  - Smith, Gertrude. 1 letter; 1950., (794)
  - Smith, Harry De Forest. 2 letters; 1933-1935., (795)
  - Smith, (Mrs.) Harry De Forest. 1 letter; [n.d.], (796)
  - Smith, Kendall Kerfoot. 4 letters; [1908]-1924., (797)
  - Smith, Priscilla M.L. 1 letter; [n.d.], (798)
  - Smith, Stanley Barney. 1 letter; 1945., (799)
  - Smith, Wendell P. 1 letter; 1960., (800)
  - Smyth, Herbert Weir, 1857-1937. 6 letters; 1921-1935., (801)
  - Snell, Bertrand Hollis, 1870-1958. 1 letter; 1931., (802)
  - Snipes, Joseph F. 1 letter; 1928., (803)
  - Snowden, Frank Martin, Jr. 2 letters; 1952-1961. see also no.(924), (804)
  - Solmsen, Friedrich, 1904- 6 letters; 1936-1962., (805)
  - Soule, William E. 1 letter; 1942., (806)
  - Souter, Alexander, 1873-1949. 8 letters; 1908-1940., (807)
  - Spaeth, John William, 1895- 1 letter; 1933., (808)
  - Spencer, Theodore, 1902-1949. 1 letter; 1947., (809)
  - Sperry, Willard Learoyd, 1882-1954. 17 letters; 1932-1954. No.4 signed by secretary., (810)
  - Spring, Evelyn, 1 letter, 1922., (811)
  - Stacey, Ellen Louise. 2 letters; 1932-1953., (812)
  - Stannard, Jerry. 1 letter; 1957., (813)
  - Stearns, Alfred Ernest, 1871- 6 letters; 1927-1938., (814)
  - Stearns, Anna. 1 letter; [n.d.], (815)
  - Stearns, Charles W. 1 letter; 1929., (816)
  - Stearns, Foster, 1881- 1 letter; 1936., (817)
  - Stearns, Frank W. 6 letters; 1927-1938. No.6 signed by secretary., (818)
  - Stearns, John Barker, 1894- 2 letters; 1929-1936., (819)
  - Steele, Frederic L. 4 letters; 1954-1960., (820)
  - Steele, Robert Benson, 1860- 1 letter; 1920., (821)
  - [Stevenson, George S.] 1 letter; 1941., (822)
  - Stewart, Zeph, 1921- 8 letters; 1949-1963 and [n.d.], (823)
  - Stinchcomb, James. 3 letters; 1941-1944., (824)
  - Stocker, Arthur Frederick. 23 letters; 1939-1946 and [n.d.] No.10 - see also A.F. Stocker to John H. Finley, no.(1138) Nos 11 and 14 - see also A.F. Stocker to the Sheldon Committee, no.(1140) No. 13 - see also C.D. Gray to A.F. Stocker, no.(1050) No.17 - see also A.F. Stocker to Florence K. Leetch, no.(1139), (825)
  - Stone, Harlan Fiske, 1872-1946. 3 letters; 1927-1932 and [n.d.], (826)
  - Stone, Marshall Harvey, 1903- 1 letter; [n.d.], (827)
  - Stonehill, Gerald Charles. 5 letters; [1944]-1951., (828)
  - Strickley, Alexander. 2 letters; 1931., (829)
  - Strittmatter, Anselm. 1 letter; 1944., (830)
  - Strong, Richard Pearson, 1872-1948. 1 letter; 1938., (831)
  - Strzelecki, Wladyslaw. 1 letter; 1948., (832)
  - Stuart, Duane Reed, 1873- 1 letter; 1921., (833)
  - Stuart, Meriwether, 1905- 4 letters; 1951-1953., (834)
  - Stuart-Jones, Sir Henry, 1867-1939. 1 letter; 1921., (835)
  - Sturtevant, Edgar Howard, 1875-1952. 1 letter; [n.d.] Concerning the American Philological Association., (836)
  - Sumner, George Steadman. 1 letter; 1932. Concerning William Fisher., (837)
  - Taccone, Angelo. 1 letter; 1931., (838)
  - Tanner, Rollin Harvelle, 1874- 1 letter; 1929. Signed by secretary., (839)
  - Tarbell, Frank Bigelow, 1853-1920. 2 letters; 1913-1916., (840)
  - Tavenner, Eugene, 1878- 8 letters; 1916-[1947] No.4 - see also Tavenner to Eugene Fairclough, no.(1141), (841)
  - Taylor, Charles Lincoln, 1901- 2 letters; 1946., (842)
  - Taylor, John H. 1 letter; 1948., (843)
  - Taylor, Lily Ross, 1886- 10 letters; 1939-1953 and [n.d.], (844)
  - Tea, Eva, 1886- 1 letter; 1929., (845)
  - Tenney, Merrill Chapin, 1904- 1 letter; [n.d.], (846)
  - Thatcher, Roscoe Wilfred, 1872-1933. 3 letters; 1930-1932., (847)
  - Thayer, J. Appleton. 3 letters; 1954-1955., (848)
  - Thayer, William G. 2 letters; 1928-1929., (849)
  - Thiaulcourt, Camille, 1854- 1 letter; 1922., (850)
  - Thompson, Alexander Mackenzie. 1 letter; [1956], (851)
  - Thompson, Homer A. 1 letter; 1950., (852)
  - Thompson, Stith, 1885- 2 letters; 1935., (853)
  - Thomson, James Alexander Kerr, 1879-1959. 4 letters; 1920., (854)
  - Thomson, Margaret H. 2 letters; 1962., (855)
  - Thomson, William, 1889- 4 letters; 1936-1953., (856)
  - Throop, George Reeves. 2 letters; 1924-1933., (857)
  - Thwing, Charles Franklin, 1853-1937. 3 letters; 1927-1931., (858)
  - Ticknor, Thomas B. 1 letter; 1908., (859)
  - Tilton, Olive Fobes. 1 letter; [n.d.], (860)
  - Titchener, John Bradford, 1898- 1 letter; 1924., (861)
  - Tobey, Charles William, 1880-1953. 2 letters; 1952., (862)
  - [Toll], Katherine. 1 telegram; 1932., (863)
  - Topping, Eva C. 1 letter; 1957., (864)
  - Torrey, Charles Cutler, 1863-1956. 6 letters; 1920-1954., (865)
  - Tozzer, Alfred Marston, 1877-1954. 1 letter; 1946., (866)
  - Travis, Albert Hartman. 16 letters; 1941-1961., (867)
  - Treadway, Allen Towner, 1867-1947. 3 letters; 1927-1934., (868)
  - Tryon, Rolla Milton, 1916- 1 letter; 1961., (869)
  - Tuckerman, Frederick, 1857- 1 telegram; 1924., (870)
  - Turyn, Aleksander, 1900- 9 letters; 1943-1954., (871)
  - Tweedy, Henry Hallam, 1868- 1 letter; 1932., (872)
  - Tyler, John Mason, 1851-1929. 1 letter; 1928., (873)
  - Ullman, Berthold Louis, 1882- 5 letters; 1922-1948 and [n.d.], (873a)
  - Underhill, Miriam. 10 letters; 1960-1961 and [n.d.], (874)
  - Upson, Hollis Ritchie. 4 letters; 1940-1943., (875)
  - Upton, Robert William, 1884- 1 letter; 1954., (876)
  - Van Hook, La Rue, 1877- 3 letters; 1921-1947., (877)
  - Van Horne, John, 1889- 12 letters; 1929-1946 and [n.d.], (878)
  - Wachs, W.C. 1 letter; 1945., (879)
  - Wagenblass, John Henry. 1 letter; 1938., (880)
  - Wagenvoort, Hendrik, 1886- 2 letters; 1949., (881)
  - Waites, Margaret Coleman. 1 letter; 1923., (882)
  - Waldrop, George B. 3 letters; 1941-1946., (883)
  - Wallace, Maloolm Vincent Timothy. 23 letters; 1950-1958 and [n.d.] See also no.(924), (884)
  - Walsh, David Ignatius, 1872-1947. 4 letters; 1932-1941., (885)
  - Walton, Francis Redding. 8 letters; 1936-1955 and [n.d.] No.8 lacks beginning., (886)
  - Warmington, Eric Herbert, 1898- 3 letters; 1942-1952., (887)
  - Warsher, Tatiana. 1 letter; [n.d.], (888)
  - Washburn, Arthur. 1 letter; [1962], (889)
  - Washburn, Benjamin Martin. 3 letters; 1951-1957., (890)
  - Washburn, Bradford, 1910- 1 letter; [n.d.], (891)
  - Washburn, Henrietta (Pease) 43 letters; [1918]-[1962] and [n.d.], (892)
  - Washburn, Henry Bradford, 1869- 43 letters; 1928-1961 and [n.d.], (893)
  - Washburn, Sherwood Larned, 1911- 9 letters; 1933-1961, (894)
  - Washburn, Stanley. 11 letters; 1952-[1955] and [n.d.], (895)
  - Washburn, Tuck. 14 letters; [1947]-1957 and [n.d.], (896)
  - Wasson, Robert Gordon, 1898- 7 letters; 1953-1956., (897)
  - Waszink, A. 1 letter; 1955., (898)
  - Waszink, Jan Hendrik, 1908- 7 letters; 1952- 1958., (899)
  - Wattles, Gurdon Wallace. 3 letters; [1942]-1945 and [n.d.], (900)
  - Webster, Edwin. 1 letter; 1935., (901)
  - Weigle, Luther Allan, 1880- 2 letters; 1931., (902)
  - Weinreich, Otto, 1886- 1 letter; 1921., (903)
  - Weinstock, Stefan. 1 letter; 1937., (904)
  - Wellman, Gordon Boit. 2 letters; 1936., (905)
  - Wells, Theodore W. 17 letters; [1957]-1962 and [n.d.], (906)
  - Wernaer, Robert Maximilian, 1865- 1 letter; 1941., (907)
  - Westgate, Reginald Isaac Wilfred. 9 letters; 1936-1959, (908)
  - Wetmore, Monroe Nichols, 1863- 3 letters; 1923-1931., (909)
  - Whatmough, Joshua, 1897-1964. 20 letters; 1933-1959., (910)
  - Wheeler, Arthur Leslie, 1871-1932. 1 letter; 1914., (911)
  - Whicher, George Meason, 1860- 7 letters; 1922-1941 and [n.d.], (912)
  - White, Alain Campbell, 1880- 2 letters; 1949., (913)
  - White, John Williams, 1849-1917. 1 letter; 1909., (914)
  - Whiteley, S. 2 letters; 1941-1942., (915)
  - Whiting, Bartlett Jere, 1904- 1 letter; 1953., (916)
  - Whiting, Edward Elwell, 1875- 1 letter; 1931., (917)
  - Whiting, William Fairfield, 1864-1936. 1 letter; 1928., (918)
  - Whitney, H. Monroe. 2 letters; 1945., (919)
  - Wild, Ada G. 1 letter; 1941., (920)
  - Wild, Henry Douglas. 3 letters; 1928-1933., (921)
  - Williams, Charles Allyn, 1877- 2 letters; 1934., (922)
  - Williams, Theodore Chickering, 1855-1915. 1 letter; 1897., (923)
  - Willis, William H. 2 letters; 1950-1953., (924)
  - Wilson, Edith (Bolling), 1872- 1 letter; 1932., (925)
  - Wilson, Edwin Bidwell, 1879-1964. 1 letter; 1939., (926)
  - Wilson, Eugene. 1 letter; 1944., (927)
  - Winter, John Garrett, 1881- 2 letters; 1946., (928)
  - Wise, Konrad Pittwood. 1 letter; 1944., (929)
  - Wissowa, J. 2 letters; 1921-1923., (930)
  - Wittgenstein, Paul. 1 letter; 1945., (931)
  - Wolfson, Harry Austryn, 1887- 1 letter; 1944., (932)
  - Woodbridge, Frederick James Eugene, 1867-1940. 4 letters; 1927-1936., (933)
  - Woodbury, Leonard Ernest. 20 letters; 1942-1958 and [n.d.], (934)
  - Woodbury, Marjorie. 2 letters; 1944 and [n.d.], (935)
  - Woods, Paul D. 1 letter; [n.d.], (936)
  - Woodworth, Allegra. 3 letters; [1957]-1961 and [n.d.], (937)
  - Woodworth, Katharine. 3 letters; 1953-[1961], (938)
  - Wooley, Philip F. 1 letter; 1951., (939)
  - Woolley, Mary Emma, 1863- 6 letters; 1928-1931. Nos.1 and 2 signed by secretary., (940)
  - Wright, Horace Wetherill, 1884- 7 letters; 1932-1939., (941)
  - Wright, John Henry, 1852-1908. 1 letter; 1900., (942)
  - Wrist, Edward C. 3 letters; 1936-1937., (943)
  - Wyatt, William Frank, 1922- 4 letters; 1937., (944)
  - Wyckoff, Elizabeth. 2 letters; 1947., (945)
  - Wyman, Jeffries, Jr. 2 letters; [n.d.], (946)
  - Yearnes, Herbert H. 2 letters; 1957., (947)
  - Young, Clarence H. 1 telegram.; 1926., (948)
  - Zeitlin, Jacob, 1883- 6 letters; 1926-1929., (949)
  - Zielinski, Tadeusz, 1859-1944. 2 letters; 1923., (950)
  - Zinsser, Hans, 1878-1940. 1 letter; 1934, (951)
  - Unidentified. 35 letters; [v.d.], (952)
- II. Letters from Arthur Stanley Pease.
  Letters from Arthur Stanley Pease to various correspondents.
  - Academic press, recipient. 1 letter; 1958., (953)
  - Academic record, recipient. 1 letter; [1945], (954)
  - American council of learned societies, recipient. 2 letters; 1951-[1961] No.1 concerns M.V.T. Wallace; no.2 concerns Frank Snowden., (955)
  - American philological association, Monograph committee, recipient. 9 letters; 1933-1935., (956)
  - American philological association. Nominating committee, recipient. 1 letter; 1946., (957)
  - Amherst college, recipient. 2 letters; 1931-1932., (958)
  - Ball, Allen P., recipient. 1 letter; 1932., (959)
  - Bassett, Samuel Eliot, d. 1936, recipient. 1 letter; 1935., (960)
  - Benner, Allen Rogers, recipient. 1 letter; [1938], (961)
  - Blachly, Lou, recipient. 1 letter 1959., (962)
  - Bonner, Campbell, 1876-, recipient. 1 letter; [1943], (963)
  - Boynton, Morrison Russell, recipient. 1 letter; 1951., (964)
  - Brill, E.J., publishers, recipient. 1 letter; 1958., (965)
  - Brownson, Carleton Lewis, 1866-, recipient. 1 letter; 1936., (966)
  - Calhoun, George Miller, 1886-1942, recipient. 1 letter; 1937., (967)
  - Cameron, Donald, recipient. 1 letter; 1938., (968)
  - Canter, Howard Vernon, 1873-, recipient. 1 letter; [1941], (969)
  - Carpenter, Charles Carroll, 1836-1918, recipient. 1 letter; 1895., (970)
  - Chamberlin, Henry Harmon, 1873-, recipient. 1 letter; 1942., (971)
  - Clausen, Wendell Vernon, 1923-, recipient. 1 letter; 1956., (972)
  - Comstock, Ada Louise, 1876-, recipient. 1 letter; [n.d.], (973)
  - Conant, James Bryant, 1893-, recipient. 2 letters; 1938-[1944], (974)
  - Cortright, E. Everett, recipient. 1 letter; 1931., (975)
  - Cowling, Donald John, 1880- 1 letter; 1931., (976)
  - Cox, Channing Harris, 1879-, recipient. 1 letter; 1930., (977)
  - Cutter, Elijah, recipient. 1 letter; 1889., (978)
  - Dewey, Harry P., recipient. 1 letter; 1932., (979)
  - Dow, Sterling, 1903-, recipient. 2 letters; 1954-1961. No.2 with a note by Sterling Dow., (980)
  - Eames, Edward W., recipient. 1 letter; 1930., (981)
  - Eliot, Samuel Atkins, 1862-1950, recipient. 1 letter; 1928., (982)
  - Frank, Tenney, 1876-1939, recipient. 1 letter; 1935., (983)
  - Graustein, Jeannette Elizabeth, 1916-, recipient. 1 letter; 1961., (984)
  - Greene, William Chase, 1890-, recipient. 1 letter; 1954., (985)
  - Gulick, Charles Burton, 1868-, recipient. 1 letter; [n.d.], (986)
  - Hadzsits, George Depue, 1875-, recipient. 3 letters; 1944-1945., (987)
  - Hahn, E. Adelaide, recipient. 1 letter; [1944], (988)
  - Hall, Norman A., recipient. 1 letter; 1954., (989)
  - Harmon, Austin M., recipient. 1 letter; 1945., (990)
  - Harvard university press, recipient. 3 letters; 1934-1958 and [n.d.], (991)
  - Hatch, Robert McConnell, bp., 1910-, recipient. 1 letter; [1951], (992)
  - Hanfmann, [ ], recipient. 1 letter; 1954., (993)
  - Heller, John Lewis, recipient. 1 letter; [1957], (994)
  - Hendrickson, George Lincoln, 1865-, recipient. 2 letters; 1942., (995)
  - Herescu, Niculae I., recipient. 1 letter; [n.d.], (996)
  - Hewitt, Joseph William, 1875-1938, recipient. 3 letters; 1933-1935., (997)
  - Hincks, Carroll C., recipient. 1 letter; 1930., (998)
  - Number omitted from series., (999)
  - Jacobs, Thornwell, 1877- 1 letter; 1932., (1000)
  - Jaeger, Ruth. 1 letter; 1961., (1001)
  - Jaeger, Werner Wilhelm, 1888-1961, recipient. 1 letter; 1946., (1002)
  - Jordan, Wilbur Kitchener, 1902-, recipient. 1 letter; [1948], (1003)
  - Kent, Roland Grubb, 1877-1952, recipient. 1 letter; 1946., (1004)
  - King, Stanley, 1883-, recipient. 3 letters; 1927-[1933] and [n.d.], (1005)
  - Kline, W.A., recipient. 1 letter; 1940., (1006)
  - Livingstone, Sir Richard Winn, 1880-1957, recipient. 1 letter; [1941], (1007)
  - Lord, Louis Eleazer, 1875-1957, recipient. 1 letter; 1944., (1008)
  - McCord, David, 1897-, recipient. 2 letters; 1961 and [n.d.], (1009)
  - McKinley, W.B., recipient. 1 letter; 1912. By Pease and others., (1010)
  - McNamee, Barbara, recipient. 1 letter; [1961], (1011)
  - Marsh, Daniel Lash, 1880-, recipient. 1 letter; 1930., (1012)
  - Moore, Frank Gardner, 1865-, recipient. 1 letter; [1937], (1013)
  - Moore, John, recipient. 1 letter; [1946], (1014)
  - Morison, Samuel Eliot, 1887-, recipient. 2 letters; 1933-1934., (1015)
  - Myerson, Abraham, 1881-1948, recipient. 1 letter; [1942], (1016)
  - Nock, Arthur Darby, 1902-1963, recipient. 3 letters; 1933-1954., (1017)
  - Oldfather, William Abbott, 1880-1945, recipient. 8 letters; 1934-1944 and [n.d.], (1018)
  - Oliver, Revilo Pendleton, 1910-, recipient. 1 letter; 1947., (1019)
  - Paradise, Scott Hurtt, 1891-, recipient. 1 letter; 1957., (1020)
  - Pearson, Roy Messer, 1914-, recipient. 1 letter; [1957], (1021)
  - Pease, [ ], recipient. 5 letters; 1891-[1893] and [n.d.], (1022)
  - Pease, Theodore Claudius, d.1893. 2 letters; 1891., (1023)
  - Pharr, Clyde, 1883-, recipient. 1 letter; 1942., (1024)
  - Plumpe, Joseph Conrad, 1901-, recipient. 1 letter; [1940], (1025)
  - Poole, James Plummer, recipient. 1 letter; 1961., (1026)
  - Porter, C. Scott, recipient. 1 letter; 1961., (1027)
  - Rand, Edward Kennard, 1871-1945, recipient. 2 letters; [1938]-1939., (1028)
  - Reiter, Siegfried, recipient. 1 letter; 1908., (1029)
  - Richards, John Francis Chatterton, recipient. 1 letter; [n.d.], (1030)
  - Roebuck, Carl Angus, 1914-, recipient. 1 letter; [1955], (1031)
  - Sachs, Paul Joseph, 1878-1965, recipient. 1 letter; 1945., (1032)
  - Sanders, Henry Arthur, 1868-, recipient. 1 letter; 1943., (1033)
  - Scaife, Roger Livingston, 1875- 1 letter; 1945., (1034)
  - Schultes, Richard Evans, recipient. 3 letters; 1959-1962., (1035)
  - Scott, James E., recipient. 1 letter; 1930., (1036)
  - Seigle, Samuel B., recipient. 1 letter; [1956], (1037)
  - Shero, Lucius Rogers, recipient. 1 letter; 1954., (1038)
  - Sherwood, (Mrs.) G.H., recipient. 1 letter; 1923., (1039)
  - Sinnen, Jean, recipient. 1 letter; 1960., (1040)
  - Smith, Gertrude, recipient. 1 letter; [1950], (1041)
  - Smith, (Mrs.) Harry De Forest, recipient. 2 letters; 1943., (1042)
  - Stearns, Frank W., recipient. 1 letter; [n.d.], (1043)
  - Thayer, J. Appleton, recipient. 1 letter; 1955., (1044)
  - Torrey, Charles Cutler, 1863-1956, recipient. 1 letter; [1953], (1045)
  - Travis, Albert Hartman, recipient. 1 letter; 1946., (1046)
  - Underhill, Miriam, recipient. 1 letter; 1961., (1047)
  - U.S. Social security administration, recipient. 1 letter; 1963., (1048)
  - Wasson, Robert Gordon, 1898-, recipient. 2 letter; 1956., (1049)
  - Weigle, Luther Allen, 1880-, recipient. 1 letter; 1931., (1050)
  - Young, Francis A. 1 letter; [1954], (1051)
  - Unidentified. 5 letters; 1923-[1955] and [n.d.], (1052)
- III. Other letters
  - Abbott, Laurence Fraser, 1859-1933. 1 letter to Esther H. Stocks; 1931., (1053)
  - Academic press. 10 letters (copies) to Richard Evans Schultes; 1962-1963., (1054)
  - Badische, Landesbibliothek. 1 letter to J.B. Hofmann; 1923., (1055)
  - Bailey, Albert Edward, 1871- 1 letter (copy) to Frederick Harlan Page; 1932., (1056)
  - Baker, Ray Stannard, 1870-1946. 4 letters to Henrietta (Faxon) Pease; 1933-1937., (1057)
  - Bassett, Edward Lewis, 1914- 1 letter to Mason Hammond; [n.d.], (1058)
  - Beach, Ella. 1 letter to Henrietta (Faxon) Pease; [n.d.], (1059)
  - Benton, William, 1900- 1 letter (mimeographed) to Harry S. Truman; 1959., (1060)
  - Blake, Warren Everett. 1 letter to Charles Burton Gulick; 1936., (1061)
  - Bonner, Campbell, 1876- 1 letter (copy) to Robert M. Hutching; 1943., (1062)
  - Bowman, Isaiah, 1878-1950. 1 letter to Levi Arnold Post; 1946., (1063)
  - Calhoun, George Miller, 1886-1942. 2 letters (copies) to Alfred Gudeman; 1937., (1064)
  - Calhoun, George Miller, 1886-1942. 1 letter (copy) to Levi Arnold Post; 1937., (1065)
  - Calhoun, George Miller, 1886-1942. 1 letter (copy) to Lily Ross Taylor; 1939. With a note by Arthur Stanley Pease., (1066)
  - Cannon, Walter Bradford, 1871-1945. 1 letter (copy) to Edward Kennard Rand; 1938., (1067)
  - Capozzi, Francis Clement, 1885- 1 letter (copy) to [Carl Newell] Jackson; 1935., (1068)
  - Capps, Edward, 1866- 1 letter to [Allen Rogers] Benner; 1939., (1069)
  - Caulfield, G.F. 1 letter to Theodore Claudius Pease; 1875., (1070)
  - Chamberlin, Henry Harmon, 1873- 1 letter to Edward Kennard Rand; 1942., (1071)
  - Comfort, William Wistar, 1874- 1 letter to Henrietta (Faxon) Pease; 1938., (1072)
  - Coolidge, Grace (Goodhue) 1879-1957. 1 letter to Henrietta (Faxon) Pease; 1929., (1073)
  - DeBra, H.R. 1 letter (copy) to Frederick Harlan Page; 1932., (1074)
  - Dewson, (Mrs.) G.B. 1 letter to Henrietta (Faxon) Pease; 1909., (1075)
  - Downey, Glanville, 1908- 2 letters (copies) to Lily Ross Taylor; 1938-1939., (1076)
  - Esty, Annette; 1 letter to Henrietta (Faxon) Pease; [n.d.], (1077)
  - Fernald, Merritt Lyndon, 1873- 1 letter to Carl Newell Jackson; 1946., (1078)
  - Fobes, Francis Howard, d.1957. 1 letter to Henrietta (Faxon) Pease; 1950., (1079)
  - Fuess, Claude Moore, 1885-1963. 1 letter to Henrietta (Faxon) Pease; 1928., (1080)
  - Funaioli, Gino, 1878- 1 letter to Edward Kennard Rand; 1937. Copy in the hand of Arthur Stanley Pease., (1081)
  - Gray, Clifton Daggett, 1874- 1 letter (copy) to Arthur Frederick Stocker; 1941., (1082)
  - Greene, Jerome Davis, 1874- 1 letter to John Huston Finley; 1942., (1083)
  - Greene, William Chase, 1890- 1 letter (copy) to Eric Alfred Havelock; 1946., (1084)
  - Gudeman, Alfred, 1862- 1 letter (copy) to George Miller Calhoun; 1936., (1085)
  - Gummere, Richard Mott, 1883- 1 letter (copy) to the American Scholar; 1941., (1086)
  - Hadzsits, George Depue, 1875- 1 letter to Austin M. Harmon; 1945., (1087)
  - Hadzsits, George Depue, 1875- 1 letter (copy) to George Lincoln Hendrickson; 1942. With a copy in the hand of Arthur Stanley Pease., (1088)
  - Hadzsits, George Depue, 1875- 1 letter to Edward Kennard Rand; 1943., (1089)
  - Halliday, William Reginald, 1886- 2 letters to Henrietta (Faxon) Pease; 1925., (1090)
  - Hammond, Mason, 1903- 1 letter (copy) to [Edward Lewis] Bassett; 1942., (1091)
  - Hammond, Mason, 1903- 1 letter (copy) to [Harry] Caplan; 1940., (1092)
  - Hammond, Mason, 1903- 1 letter (copy) to [Irene] Nye; 1940., (1093)
  - Hammond, Mason, 1903- 1 letter to Henrietta (Faxon) Pease; 1951., (1094)
  - [Harmon] 1 letter to [Edward Capps]; [1945], (1095)
  - Harmon, Austin M. 3 letters (copies) to William Abbott Oldfather; 1938-1944., (1096)
  - Harris, George. 1 telegram to Theodore Claudius Pease; 1893-, (1097)
  - Harvard university press. 1 letter (copy) to Werner Wilhelm Jaeger; 1950., (1098)
  - Harvard University Press. 1 letter (copy) to Richard Evans Schultes; 1961., (1099)
  - Heidel, William Arthur, 1868-1941. 1 letter to [Charles Melville] Moss; 1923., (1100)
  - Hendrickson, George Lincoln, 1865- 1 letter (copy) to Werner Wilhelm Jaeger; 1942., (1101)
  - Herrick, Everett Carleton. 1 letter to Henrietta (Faxon) Pease; 1932., (1102)
  - Hilliger, [Benno], 1863-1944. 1 letter to J.B. Hofmann; 1923., (1103)
  - Hodgman, Arthur Winfred. 1 letter to Edward Kennard Rand; 1945., (1104)
  - Hopkins, Ernest M. 1 letter to Adolph F. Pauli; 1922., (1104a)
  - Hubbard, George R, 1 letter to Edgar Johnson; [n.d.], (1105)
  - Hunnewell, F.W. 1 letter to [George Rice] Cooley; [n.d.], (1106)
  - Jones, Lester M. 1 letter (copy) to Frederick Harlan Page; 1932., (1107)
  - Kent, Roland Grubb, 1877-1952. 1 letter (copy) to [Eric Herbert] Warmington; 1947., (1108)
  - Keyes, Frances Parkinson (Wheeler) 1885- 1 letter to Henrietta (Faxon) Pease; 1953., (1109)
  - King, Stanley, 1883- 1 letter (copy) to Howard Dykema Roelofs; 1935., (1110)
  - Kraeling, Carl Hermann, 1897- 1 letter (copy) to Luther Allan Weigle; 1932., (1111)
  - Kretschmer, F. 1 letter to Carl Newell Jackson; 1937., (1112)
  - Lancaster press, Lancaster, Pa. 1 letter to Joseph William Hewitt; 1934., (1113)
  - Leland, Waldo Gifford, 1879- 1 letter(copy) to George Miller Calhoun; 1936. With another copy., (1114)
  - Linforth, Ivan Mortimer, 1879- 2 letters to William Abbott Oldfather; 1944., (1115)
  - Lowell, Abbott Lawrence, 1856-1943. 1 letter to Henrietta (Faxon) Pease; 1933., (1116)
  - McCord, David, 1897- 1 letter (copy) to Mabel Hall Colgate; 1956., (1117)
  - McCord, David, 1897- 1 letter (copy) to Frederick Foster; 1956., (1118)
  - McDonald, Mabel C. 1 letter to Henrietta (Faxon) Pease; 1922., (1119)
  - McElwain, Mary B. 1 letter to Henrietta (Faxon) Pease; 1955., (1120)
  - McFall, Jack K. 1 letter (mimeographed) Henry Cabot Lodge; 1951., (1121)
  - Miller, Charles Roger Donahue. 1 letter to Mason Hammond; 1945., (1122)
  - Moore, George Foot, 1851-1931. 1 letter to Henrietta (Faxon) Pease; [1924], (1123)
  - Moore, Mary (Hanford) d.1924. 2 letters to Henrietta (Faxon) Pease; [1924] and [n.d.], (1124)
  - Mott, Marshall E. 1 letter to Henry Bradford Washburn; 1944., (1125)
  - Munn, James Buell. 1 letter (copy) to Haven Darling Brackett; 1938., (1126)
  - Norden, Marie. 1 letter to Henrietta (Faxon) Pease; 1936., (1127)
  - Norton, Sara. 1 letter to George Foot Moore; 1909., (1128)
  - Noyes, Charles Lothrop, 1851-1923. 1 letter to Abby [Frances (Cutter) Pease]; 1921., (1129)